# MANOHAR SHETTY

### DEVOPS ENGINEER

**©** 

+91 7386120507 / 7977651305



manohar.shetty507@gmail.com



Bangalore, India



linkedin.com/in/manohar-shetty-442a90155

#### ABOUT ME

5 years of IT experience in handling Linux Servers, Virtualization and Networking which includes Planning, Implementation, Administration and Troubleshooting. Expertise in working with various DevOps tools and platform for Application Modernization, and Automation of the Deployment Process.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## DevOps Engineer

ENTERPRISE MINDS | (25-April-2023 - Present)

FLIPKART (On-site) - Embassy Tech Village, Bellandur, Bangalore-560103

#### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Deploy and manage approximately 12 Kubernetes clusters, comprising over 15,000 nodes, leveraging kubeadm, kubespray, and CAPI. Maintain the stability of the entire environment through troubleshooting, optimization efforts, and timely cluster patching and upgrades aligned with new releases
- Conduct Kubernetes cluster migrations according to project needs, implementing appropriate deployment methodologies.
- Write ansible playbooks, Jenkins pipeline, terraform files and shell scripts to automate the process, to ensure smooth deployment process.
- Handle assigned tickets in line with sprint plans to ensure timely completion and meet project goals.
- Actively address and resolve issues during on-call production support to ensure adherence to SLAs and operational stability.
- Monitor the entire environment and demonstrate a proactive approach to problemsolving, troubleshooting, and addressing the issues promptly
- Participate actively in meetings, collating relevant data, analyzing key information, and crafting comprehensive monthly reports to provide insightful updates and facilitate informed decision-making processes within the organization

# Infrastructure Specialist

**IBM India Pvt Ltd** | (09-March-2023 - 20-March-2023)

# BCIT, Block 3, Tower-A, Thanisandra, Bangalore - 560064

- Roles & Responsibilities:
  - Oversee the deployment and management of OpenShift clusters. This involves
    utilizing OpenShift deployment tools like OpenShift installer, Operator Lifecycle
    Manager (OLM), I focus on maintaining the stability and performance of the entire
    environment through constant monitoring, troubleshooting, optimization efforts, and
    ensuring timely updates and upgrades in line with OpenShift's latest releases
- Monitor the entire environment and demonstrate a proactive approach to problemsolving, troubleshooting, and addressing the issues promptly

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Kubernetes
- Redhat OpenShift
- Amazon EKS
- Cloud AWS
- IAAC Terraform
- Ansible
- Jenkins (CI-CD)
- Docker/Podman
- Shell/Bash Script
  - Python Core Knowledge
  - Argo CD
  - VMware vSphere
  - Linux RHEL / UBUNTU
  - Code & Container Scanner Snyk & Jfrog X-Ray,
     Nexus/Jfrog Artifactory
  - Monitoring Tools Prometheus, Grafana. ELK,
     etc
  - Velero Backup Kubernetes

### **DevOps Engineer**

FRONTIER BUSINESS SYSTEM | (29-Oct-2021 -10-Feb-2023)

Ashok Nagar, M G Road, Bangalore-560025

#### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Deploying and managing Kubernetes clusters using Kubeadm/Kubespray, EKS & Openshift, and provide production support as per the need
- Write Dockerfile and Kubernetes Manifest files, Helm charts as per the requirement in the project. Implement Open-Source tools (K8s backup, Code Scanner, Container Security, Auto scalar, etc) for Kubernetes/EKS in the project.
- Develop, Maintain and support Continuous Integration & Deployment framework based on Jenkins, and used Helm/Kustomize to version control complete deployment strategies.
- Write Ansible play books & Shell Scripts to automate the daily repetitive tasks
- Actively monitoring (Install Prometheus & Grafana, ELK) and alerts. Create dashboards for effectively monitoring the process activities and fatal errors.

## Trainer

INFINX SERVICES PVT LTD | (04-March-2020 - 02-Feb-2021)

Maheshwaram, Hyderabad-500005

#### Roles & Responsibilities

- · Maintain the learning portals hosted in VMware vSphere
- Train the team on private cloud Ovirt Open Virtualization, and give in-depth understanding of managing the Installation of software/applications required for the job.
- Create training modules and provide training to the internal employees on Linux and Private Cloud
- Creating and Manging Virtual Machines, Creating Templates/snapshots of the VM as per the requirements
- Allocating cloud Resources to End Users based on Project Requirement.
- Providing data for weekly and monthly report to senior management.

### Training - TL

**CONNEQT BUSINESS SOLUTIONS PVT LTD** | (22-Nov-2018 to 03-Mar-2020) Gowra Trinity, Begumpet, Hyderabad-500016

### Roles & Responsibilities

- Train the internal employees on Red Hat Administration, create modules, and generate reports and provide support to the Team
- Maintain the servers Installation, Monitoring and managing performance of ESXi servers and Virtual Machines
- Installation and Managing of DC, ADC, DNS, DHCP, updating and remove software packages with RPM and YUM. Resolve the issues by providing Onsite support on end user's desktops. Attend user queries, Maintenance & Troubleshooting of PC's, LAN,
- Perform daily server monitoring, verify the integrity and availability of all hardware, server resources, systems and key processes, reviewing system and application logs, and verifying completion of scheduled jobs such as backups

# CERTIFICATION

- Kubernetes Certified
   Administrator (CKA)
- Prometheus Certified
   Associate (PCA)
- AWS Solutions Architect Associate (SAA-02)
- Microsoft Azure Certified
   AZ900
- Oracle Cloud Certified
   Infrastructure Associate
- Gitops Certified for Argo CD

# EDUCATION

O

Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech) Aware College of Science & Technology, JNTUH (2011 - 2015)